<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- <?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://www.xml-sitemaps.com/sitemap.xsl"?> -->
<urlset
      xmlns="http://www.sitemaps.org/schemas/sitemap/0.9"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
      xmlns:video="http://www.google.com/schemas/sitemap-video/1.1"
      xsi:schemaLocation="
            http://www.sitemaps.org/schemas/sitemap/0.9
            http://www.sitemaps.org/schemas/sitemap/0.9/sitemap.xsd">

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-52-weeks-52-worksheets-package-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' 52 Lessons for 52 weeks!</video:title>
         <video:description>This packet contains a collection of 52 language and social communication worksheets, handouts, and activities that can fill a year's worth of weekly sessions for speech language pathologists, counselors, and teachers.  The social skills resources cover conversation skills, kinesics, perspective taking, development of empathy, and real-world communication.  The writing skills resources include lessons on linguistic flexibility, clarity of writing, descriptiveness, elaboration, organization, and transitional words and phrases, along with scaffolds for character descriptions and movie reviews.  The grammar resources cover subject-verb agreement, noun-pronoun agreement, perspective consistency, parallelism, and more.  The reading comprehension resources cover prefixes, suffixes, word roots, using context clues, conceptual relationships, and the identification of main ideas.  All resources have been created by a speech language pathologist with over thirty years of experience working with adolescents.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sg2Yc_5zbUI</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/adhd-worksheets-for-children</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-adhd-worksheets-for-child-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Conversation Skills: - Narratives: Set The Scene Activity Worksheet in PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Narratives: Set the Scene is an invaluable resource designed to assist individuals with attention deficit disorders, impaired executive skills functioning, or on the autism spectrum in developing their storytelling abilities in a structured, comprehensive, and engaging manner that promotes effective communication. Many of my students facing challenges related to A.S.D. or attention deficit disorders often struggle to respond to basic inquiries, such as 'tell me about your summer' or 'describe your internship experience.' Frequently, they begin narrating without offering any contextual details, such as their location, companions, or the timeframe of the event. Individuals grappling with theory of mind find it challenging to empathize with others' perspectives. Consequently, when recounting personal experiences, they tend to focus solely on their own understanding and struggle to consider what their listener may not already know but needs to. With the creation of Narratives: Set the Scene, I sought to address this specific skill and discovered that it offers a straightforward and tangible approach for students to remember to provide needed details at the onset of a verbal narrative and practice delivering it effectively. The Narratives: Set the Scene social skills activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/8PsHcOfrDu4</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/speech-therapy-worksheet-communication-skills-questionnaire-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-communication-skills-questionnaire-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Communication Skills Questionnaire PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This questionnaire offers students the opportunity to identify the specific skills they would like to enhance within various categories. These categories include Conversational Skills (e.g., selecting engaging topics, maintaining and shifting eye contact), Practical Skills (e.g., seeking assistance in a store, placing orders in a restaurant), Non-Verbal Skills (e.g., interpreting facial expressions and body language, respecting personal space), Dating Skills (e.g., initiating a date invitation, choosing suitable activities), and Conflict Resolution Skills (e.g., advocating for oneself, addressing misunderstandings). Giving students this questionnaire gives teachers, speech language pathologists, and therapists insight into which skills are significant to individual students. Furthermore, it enhances students' self-awareness and equips them with valuable information regarding possible areas of improvement to focus on. The Communication Skills Questionnaire PDF is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/IvN_tQXpLH4</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/a-conversation-activity-worksheet-for-autistic-teens</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-conversation-worksheets-for-autism-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Social Skills Activity: Entering Conversations</video:title>
         <video:description>This informational document offers a comprehensive overview of the essential behaviors involved in entering an ongoing conversation. It covers key aspects such as observation, physical proximity, timing, commenting/questioning, gauging acceptance, and exit strategies. The handout serves as a valuable resource for facilitating discussions and engaging in role-play activities aimed at assisting individuals on the autism spectrum in enhancing their conversational abilities and understanding of social dynamics. The Entering Conversations social skills activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/jmVOaXTZuTo</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/social-skills-worksheet-conversation-turn-taking</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-conversation-turn-taking-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Social Skills Activity: Conversational Elaboration</video:title>
         <video:description>This handout offers a collection of diverse examples showcasing various responses to the same question, leading to a conversation practice exercise. By presenting scripted responses, individuals on the autism spectrum gain a clear understanding of how elaborated answers naturally foster extended conversations. The handout commences with a written explanation of conversational elaboration and explores the nuances of social dynamics within conversations. The Conversational Elaboration social skills activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/XikFOsehO1c</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/autism-perspective-taking-worksheets-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-perspective-taking-worksheets-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Perspective Taking Worksheets: Polite Wording PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This worksheet aims to improve the ability of students to consider the perspective of their listeners and use polite language. The worksheet starts with a written explanation of the importance of modifying requests and comments based on the listener's point of view. It includes examples of courteous phrases that can be used to improve requests and opinion statements, followed by sentences that students can use to practice incorporating these phrases. This exercise encourages students to adjust their language while taking their audience into account. The Polite Wording social skills activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/oK_Rrq5X7C4</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/autism-perspective-taking-high-school</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-perspective-taking-high-school-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Tact Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This activity focuses on the development of empathy and perspective-taking. It is particularly useful for individuals on the autism spectrum who may experience challenges in these areas. The handout consists of nineteen statements that contain tactless sentiments, such as bragging, offensiveness, prejudice, inappropriateness, and over-generalization. These statements provide opportunities for students to engage in extensive discussions about others' perspectives and feelings. An answer key is included to aid in the activity. The Tact social skills activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/3H6drlyJXq0</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/autism-adolescent-therapy-activities-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-adolescent-therapy-activities-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Conversation Skills Time Sensitivity S.E.L. Activity for Autistic Students</video:title>
         <video:description>This activity focuses on improving communication skills related to time sensitivity. The activity starts with a written discussion about the importance of being mindful of a listener's time limit. Then, students roll dice to determine a hypothetical content and context for their communication. After considering the context, students estimate an appropriate time period and practice delivering their assigned content within that time limit. This social skills exercise enhances students' awareness of their listener's needs and helps them to improve their ability to effectively convey their message within a limited time frame. To achieve the best results, we recommend using this lesson in conjunction with Kinesics and Conversation Skills and Editing Verbal Narratives, as all three activities emphasize the need to tailor content to meet the needs of the communication partner. The Time Sensitivity Social Skills Activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/vpPwUzNpHoM</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/autistic-child-worksheets-kinesics-interest-vs-disinterest</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-kinesics-interest-vs-disinterest-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Kinesics: Interest vs. Disinterest Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This activity is a valuable resource for teaching kinesics, which involves accurately interpreting non-verbal social cues and applying this skill in conversations. Individuals on the autism spectrum often struggle to assess another person's interest in them, leading to social difficulties. They may initiate conversations at inappropriate times or continue speaking with someone who is not interested in engaging with them. Observing others' facial expressions, body language, actions, and interactions is crucial in determining acceptance. However, individuals on the autism spectrum typically do not naturally observe others' nonverbal cues as often or effectively as neurotypical individuals. This social skills activity provides students with practical experience in identifying signs of interest or disinterest from others, which helps them decide whether to continue or end conversations. The Kinesics:  Interest vs. Disinterest social skills activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Nfe3yU_kRQ</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/autistic-child-worksheets-improve-social-skills-teenager-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-improve-social-skills-teenager-worksheets-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Social Skills Activity: Editing Verbal Narratives for Teenagers with Autism</video:title>
         <video:description>This worksheet aims to develop the skills of listener presupposition and perspective-taking. It starts with a written discussion about the importance of considering the listener's perspective before speaking, and modifying one's requests and comments accordingly to achieve the best outcomes. The worksheet offers examples of courteous phrases that can be added to requests and opinion statements, and presents various sentences for students to incorporate these phrases. Through this exercise, students can practice modifying their language to be more considerate of their audience. The Editing Verbal Narratives social skills activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/zKLsHW_zT98</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/social-emotional-learning-activity-speaking-to-different-communicative-partners</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-letter-of-complaint-exercises-worksheet-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Speaking to Different Communicative Partners</video:title>
         <video:description>Understanding others' perspectives and being able to empathize is an important aspect of theory of mind. However, equally important is the ability to adjust one's behavior accordingly. These printable worksheets are designed to improve the communication skills of individuals on the autism spectrum by enhancing their ability to tailor their language based on their audience. After answering six questions in writing, students are required to choose which information to include or exclude based on their intended listener. Finally, they answer follow-up questions specific to the intended receiver. These worksheets encourage extended discussions about the reasoning behind the choices made. The Speaking to Different Communicative Partners social skills activity is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/1rhuyVlSxBM</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/pdf-worksheets-how-to-teach-empathy-classroom</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-how-to-teach-empathy-in-the-classroom-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Developing Empathy Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This social skills activity is designed to promote empathy by encouraging perspective-taking and conversational practice. It features an in-depth discussion about the significance of empathy, followed by detailed explanations of important concepts such as 'spatial inclusion', 'conversational participation', 'social distress', and 'mood.' Students then engage in social observation and practice determining others' perspectives using the provided handout during sessions. To reinforce their skills, they can utilize a 'homework' handout for real-world practice. Additionally, the materials come with useful notes on how to maximize their effectiveness, as well as suggestions for customized activities. This activity is one of my favorites and has been shown to be highly effective in developing empathy and perspective-taking. The Developing Empathy social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/MV01S53yLEk</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/social-skills-complaint-letter-worksheet-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-letter-of-complaint-exercises-worksheet-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Reader Presupposition: Complaint Letters Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This activity is a unique and highly effective approach to developing perspective-taking skills. It focuses on the art of writing and how to consider the reader's perspective, as well as the vital skill of modifying one's language to convey a specific impression. This activity combines both writing and social skills. The exercise begins with an actual complaint letter requesting monetary compensation, accompanied by therapy notes on how to effectively write a complaint letter sentence by sentence. The activity then progresses to novel situations from which students must compose their own complaint letters. In writing their letters, students must carefully choose their wording to give their readers two targeted impressions: that they are honest and reasonable. This activity has been proven to significantly improve students' perspective-taking abilities to a more sophisticated level. Additionally, it is worth noting that teenagers often enjoy this activity as it provides them with both permission and an expectation to voice their complaints. The Reader Presupposition: Complaint Letters social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/2zauEWybodk</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/perspective-taking-activities-autistic-child</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-perspective-taking-activities-autism-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Perspective Taking Homework Assignment Social Skills Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This social skills homework assignment is an ideal follow-up to the Developing Empathy activity. It commences with a detailed discussion on ways to aid individuals on the autism spectrum in developing empathy and perspective-taking skills, drawing from the author's professional experiences. The homework handout instructs students to observe actual social interactions and to view them from another person's perspective. The handout concludes by prompting students to consider what actions they could have taken to improve a social situation for someone in distress, thereby integrating observation, interpretation, troubleshooting, and action-taking. The Perspective Taking Homework Assignment social skills worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/BaSUdgj6kvk</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/being-a-good-conversationalist-social-skills-worksheet</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-being-a-good-conversationalist-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Being a Good Conversationalist Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This resource focuses on enhancing conversational skills, which is an area that not only individuals on the autism spectrum can benefit from but also anyone who wants to improve their communication skills. Most of us have neurotypical relatives, friends, neighbors, or colleagues who tend to monopolize conversations, interrupt frequently, or share long-winded stories with excessive details. Unfortunately, it is often challenging to address such behaviors without causing discomfort. This resource provides an opportunity for students to learn and practice social niceties and conversation skills so they don't grow up to be those friends, neighbors, and coworkers. Each aspect of being a good conversationalist is discussed, and various practice exercises are used, sometimes focusing on one aspect at a time. Please refer to the therapeutic notes for more information. The Being a Good Conversationalist social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/f5lpCnBOZMA</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/social-skills-choosing-conversation-topics</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-choosing-conversation-topics-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Choosing Conversation Topics Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>When I ask my students which social skills they would like to work on, one of the skills they often mention is choosing topics for conversation. I teach my students that a good conversation topic should meet three criteria: the participants should find it interesting, have something to say about it, and it should be appropriate for the group. However, there are exceptions to these rules. For instance, it may be acceptable to discuss sex with a family member, friend, or counselor even if it's not an appropriate topic for a different group of people. I use a handout as a checklist during group sessions. Each student and I fill out our own handout, assessing each topic based on whether it's interesting to us, relevant, and appropriate for the group. We place checkmarks or X's accordingly, and then highlight the topics that receive unanimous checks as the "good topics" to be used for conversation. I emphasize to my students that the definition of "good topics" varies depending on the individuals in the conversation. For example, while I may not find sports interesting, it could be a great topic for a different group of people. The Choosing Conversation Topics social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/JfnsFq8fq8E</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/interviewing-others-social-skills-worksheet</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-interviewing-others-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Interviewing Others Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>As discussed in Being a Good Conversationalist, I believe that showing genuine interest in learning about others is crucial to being an effective conversationalist. To foster this skill, I often ask my students to interview staff members, high school seniors, or family members, as this helps them develop several conversational skills, including the ability to respond to the interviewee's statements with comments and follow-up questions. I emphasize to my students that this skill is critical for two reasons: it extends conversations and makes the other person feel truly heard. The resources provided include various forms to be used for interviews, as well as notes on therapeutic intervention. The Interviewing Others social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/VbHAi-nTrQY</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/post-conversation-questionnaire-social-skills-worksheet</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-post-conversation-questionnaire-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Post-Conversation Questionnaire Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>I regularly engage in conversations with my students, both natural and "naturalistic". The natural conversations take place during our walks to my office or at the start of our sessions. However, as a speech-language pathologist, I know that to help my students improve their conversation skills, we often have to engage in "naturalistic" conversations, which are semi-artificial in nature. During these sessions, I might focus on particular skills such as topic shifting, turn-taking, using a balance of questions and comments, or interpreting non-verbal communication. After some of these conversations, I like to have my students complete a questionnaire that addresses the importance of being curious about their conversational partner, identifying the impressions given, and analyzing non-verbal behaviors. For many students, it is helpful to review the questionnaire before the conversation so that they know what to look out for. During the conversation, I task them with paying close attention to only one person. The Post-Conversation Questionnaire social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/WxDaShnT82s</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/tone-of-voice-social-skills-worksheet</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-tone-of-voice-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Tone of Voice Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Nonverbal communication involves more than just facial expressions and body language; it also encompasses tone of voice. Tone of voice is critical in expressing and interpreting emotions and intentions, and how you say something can be just as significant as the words you use. Unfortunately, individuals on the autism spectrum often struggle with interpreting or effectively using tone of voice, making it a challenging skill to teach. To address this issue, I've developed an activity that focuses on both interpretation and use of tone of voice. Additionally, the Tone of Voice activity can serve as an evaluation tool. At my school, we have encountered students who appeared to be rude or whiny, but upon discovering that their tone of voice did not match their intentions, we gained a better understanding of how to respond to them. If you want to show your students a hilarious example of how misinterpretation can occur due to missing tone of voice in written communication, check out the YouTube video "Key and Peele: Text Message Confusion".  You may want to choose the censored version. The Tone of Voice social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/c6UQq8YJyuc</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/interpreting-non-verbal-communication-homework-social-skills-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-interpreting-non-verbal-communication-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Interpreting Non-Verbal Communication Homework Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Individuals on the autism spectrum often struggle with interpreting non-verbal communication due to their limited observation of others' behaviors. To address this issue, I assign homework that requires students to observe others and interpret non-verbal behaviors, including facial expressions, body language, and tone of voice. Before giving the assignment, we work on interpretation in various ways, such as practicing identifying non-verbal signs of different emotions in videos with the sound turned off and using the Tone of Voice activity to work on using and interpreting tone of voice. This homework assignment is different from some of my other perspective taking activities because it tasks students with interpreting others' perspectives from non-verbal behaviors rather than context. The final question of the homework is crucial because it emphasizes the importance of responding in a helpful manner to another person's feelings, not just accurately identifying them. The Interpreting Non-Verbal Communication Homework social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/0KdBWwOjWf8</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/impressions-from-appearances-social-emotional-learning-activity</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-impressions-from-appearances-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Impressions from Appearances Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>I teach my students that people tend to judge others based on their appearance, even though it may not be fair or accurate. With the Impressions from Appearances activity, I aim to raise their awareness of this phenomenon and show them that conclusions drawn from appearances can often be wrong. The activity involves filling out a form together, taking turns to be judged, and focusing on controllable appearance features such as clothing or body language. I make sure to point out that the possible impressions based on appearances are often stereotypes and encourage students to assess their accuracy. I never pressure students who feel uncomfortable to participate in the activity. The Impressions from Appearances social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/X7cI_pHzpiI</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/attaining-targeted-impressions-social-emotional-learning-activity</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-attaining-targeted-impressions-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Attaining Targeted Impressions Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>When teaching social skills like empathy and perspective taking to high school and middle school students, it's important to provide engaging and practical activities that help students develop their understanding of how to attain targeted impressions in different scenarios. One effective tool is an activity that encourages students to think about what impressions they would like to give to different people in various situations, and how they might attain those desired impressions. By engaging in this type of social skills worksheet or activity, students can become more aware of the impact of their actions and learn strategies for communicating effectively and appropriately in different contexts. Through these activities, teachers can help students develop stronger interpersonal connections, improve their communication skills, and become more successful in various areas of their lives. Ultimately, developing social skills like attaining targeted impressions is essential for building empathy, promoting understanding, and fostering a more positive and inclusive community. The Attaining Targeted Impressions social skills activity social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/SDUN6oOs1Sk</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/impressions-and-altruism-social-emotional-learning-activity</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-impressions-and-altruism-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Impressions and Altruism Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This activity, Impressions and Altruism, aims to teach students about the benefits of being kind and altruistic. The activity begins with a discussion on why being kind to others is important and how it can benefit the individual as well. It then presents five different social interactions, and students take turns rolling a die to determine with whom they will be interacting. They are then asked to answer five questions that consider both their own and the other person's feelings in the situation, and suggest actions or statements that can benefit both parties. It is important to note that in some situations, the focus is more on benefiting the other person, such as when interacting with a job interviewer or a doctor. The Impressions and Altruism social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/I3vbF_VvC_E</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/social-emotional-learning-activity-understanding-others-reference-sheet</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-understanding-others-reference-sheet-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Social Skills Understanding Others Reference Sheet</video:title>
         <video:description>video_description</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/EK7fwBENyjM</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/greetings-social-skills-worksheet</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-greetings-worksheets-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Greetings Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Individuals on the autism spectrum often struggle with understanding social customs, such as greetings. While neurotypical individuals learn to closely observe others from birth, those on the spectrum tend to observe less frequently. However, greetings are not always as simple as they may appear. For example, in a workplace setting, a quick nod may be appropriate as a greeting between acquaintances, while saying “good morning” may seem out of place. To help students on the spectrum become familiar with the many choices of greetings and when to use them, this worksheet provides a reference sheet along with paired discussions to reinforce understanding. The Greetings social skills worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/EuI2g1DgnMs</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/getting-someones-attention-social-skills-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-getting-someones-attention-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>Lisa Flowers' Getting Someone's Attention social skills activity pdf</video:title>
         <video:description>One skill that may seem simple but is actually quite complex is getting someone's attention. For example, I observed one of my students as he tried to get a teacher's attention by calling out from the doorway even though the teacher was in the middle of speaking with a coworker. To help my students practice this skill, I discuss various variables, such as open or closed doors, the staff member's activity, and location. Then, I give them a form to fill out and deliver to specific staff members, asking for their evaluation of the student's approach. This helps me identify areas where my students need more intervention and I can provide direct critique to those who are receptive. The Getting Someone's Attention social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet. </video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/yP5YtlbzIrU</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/restaurant-etiquette-social-skills-activity</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-restaurant-etiquette-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Restaurant Etiquette social skills activity pdf for 2023</video:title>
         <video:description>The Restaurant Etiquette activity focuses on developing life skills that adolescents may not have had much experience with yet, such as making a restaurant reservation and handling the check. Dining out is a social experience that involves interacting with servers, hosts, cashiers, and busboys, and therefore requires perspective taking. During this activity, I encourage my students to consider how their behaviors can impact others, such as why it's important to be polite and why it's not a good idea to arrive at a restaurant close to closing time. The Restaurant Etiquette social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/rDefTlH5hR8</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/answering-job-interview-questions-social-skills-classroom-activity</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-social-emotional-learning-activities-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Answering Job Interview Questions social skills activity pdf</video:title>
         <video:description>This worksheet is designed to help students prepare for job interviews by providing a detailed guide on how to answer the top four most commonly asked questions. It includes step-by-step instructions and numerous example answers. The worksheet emphasizes the importance of using listener presupposition, which involves considering the perspective of the interviewer when responding to questions. It encourages students to think about the impression they want to make on the interviewer and provides guidance on how to answer in a way that will create the desired impression. After reviewing the worksheet, we engage in role-playing exercises to practice these skills. The Answering Job Interview Questions social skills activity pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/xqEGEgdnubI</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/passive-aggression-social-skills-activity-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-passive-aggression-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Passive Aggression Worksheet Social Skills Activity PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>I aim to support my students in identifying and responding to passive aggression, as it can be difficult to deal with. Passive aggression involves hostile behaviors that the perpetrator tries to mask, and my students never deserve to be on the receiving end of this type of behavior. We discuss how to spot passive aggression, including examples of backhanded compliments, and how to recognize the hostility behind them. We also talk about how to respond calmly and assertively, while also taking into account the specific circumstances of each situation. By standing up for themselves, my students can discourage the perpetrator from engaging in passive aggression in the future. The Passive Aggression Worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/QGS3IuD3-U4</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/subject-verb-object-social-skills-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-subject-verb-object-worksheets-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Grammar: Subjects, Verbs, and Objects Grammar Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>To achieve proper usage of verb tense, subject-verb agreement, parallelism, and other grammatical structures, students must first learn how to identify subjects, verbs, and objects in a sentence. This two-page grammar worksheet includes an explanation of these components, as well as two tasks for students to complete: identifying the parts of speech in provided sentences and completing a fill-in-the-blank exercise. An answer key is also provided. Prepositional phrase and adverbial phrase worksheets are recommended for further practice in identifying subjects, verbs, and objects in more complex sentences. The Grammar: Subjects, Verbs, and Objects grammar worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/aN6EqRNJ1_A</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/preposition-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-preposition-worksheets-pdf-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Subjects, Verbs, and Objects, and Prepositional Phrases Grammar Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This two-page worksheet is a follow-up to the Subjects, Verbs, and Objects worksheet and focuses on teaching students how to locate these parts of speech within the "core" of sentences by first identifying and omitting prepositional phrases within those sentences. Identifying subjects, verbs, and objects is crucial to achieving subject-verb agreement, noun-pronoun agreement, and overall syntactic accuracy. This worksheet is particularly useful for high school students who may not have received much instruction in prepositions and prepositional phrases. It includes an answer key and can serve as a great resource for teaching these grammatical structures. The Subjects, Verbs, and Objects, and Prepositional Phrases grammar worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/j-hMNEYcKFo</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/adverbs-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-adverbs-worksheet-pdf-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Subjects, Verbs, and Objects, and Adverbial Phrases grammar worksheet pdf</video:title>
         <video:description>This printable worksheet is designed to teach students how to identify the essential components of complex sentences, such as subjects, verbs, and objects, by omitting unnecessary parts. Similar to my "Prepositional Phrases and Subjects, Verbs, and Objects" lesson, this worksheet specifically focuses on adverbial phrases. By breaking down sentences and recognizing these parts of speech, students can improve their ability to maintain subject-verb agreement, use the active voice, and perform well on grammar sections of standardized tests like the SAT and ACT. The worksheet includes exercises and an answer key. The Subjects, Verbs, and Objects, and Adverbial Phrases grammar worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/tEqQgkzL-QU</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/noun-pronoun-agreement-worksheet-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-noun-pronoun-agreement-worksheet-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Noun-Pronoun Agreement Grammar Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>To become adept at writing sophisticated, grammatically accurate essays, or to excel on the grammar section of standardized tests such as the SAT or ACT, one must first master noun-pronoun agreement. This two-page grammar worksheet, designed for high school students, covers the singular and plural nature of nouns and pronouns, and offers several exercises to correct mismatches based on SAT practice sentences. An answer key is provided for reference. To prepare for this worksheet, it is highly recommended to first work on the grammar worksheets related to Subjects, Verbs, and Objects, Prepositional Phrases, and Adverbial Phrases, as a student must be able to identify which noun corresponds to which pronoun in order to achieve agreement. The Noun-Pronoun Agreement Grammar Worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/LCJvmHv0A9w</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/grammar-parallelism-worksheet-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-parallelism-worksheet-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Parallelism Grammar Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>To achieve competent and sophisticated writing, high school and university students must master the use of parallel structure when listing or contrasting components of their content. This two-page worksheet is designed to improve students' skills by providing an explanation and examples of parallelism for both lists and contrasts, as well as tasks requiring them to modify grammatical structures within sentences in order to achieve parallelism. The sentences used in the worksheet are paraphrased from actual SAT practice sentences to prepare students for the higher-level grammar expectations of the SAT, ACT, and college-level English courses. The Parallelism grammar worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/dcGg-MRAl5Y</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/grammar-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-grammar-worksheets-high-school-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Grammar Worksheet Packet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This packet of grammar worksheets focuses on improving students' syntactical accuracy and writing skills. It includes several materials such as Subjects, Verbs, and Objects, SVOs and Prepositional Phrases, SVOs and Adverbial Phrases, Verb Tense, Noun-Pronoun Agreement, Subject-Verb Agreement, and Parallelism, which help students achieve accurate grammar usage. In addition, the packet includes materials on Adjectives and Adverbs for improving the descriptiveness of their writing, Passive and Active Voice to strengthen the message of their content, and Perspective Consistency to improve the clarity of their content. These worksheets are designed to give students a better understanding of the nuances of grammar, enabling them to convey their ideas clearly and make a positive impression on their audience.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/_ZGGTPPjx6M</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/word-roots-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-word-roots-pdf-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Word Roots Reading Comprehension Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Speech language pathologists know how crucial it is for students to expand their vocabulary to comprehend content. Knowing common word roots is a useful method to expand vocabulary knowledge. These two printable worksheets come with answer keys and provide 10 common word roots along with their definitions and example words. Students are then asked to define other example words in sentences and create their own sentences containing either a previous or new word. The Word Roots reading comprehension pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/9nhdxU-89K4</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/prefixes-and-suffixes-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-prefixes-and-suffixes-worksheets-pdf-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Prefixes and Suffixes Reading Comprehension Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Expanding one's receptive vocabulary is essential to improving comprehension, and a great way to achieve this is by learning the meaning of common prefixes and suffixes. These 3 printable worksheets cover both (one covers prefixes, one covers suffixes, and one covers both). By learning the meaning of common prefixes and suffixes, students can begin to understand unfamiliar words that contain these prefixes and suffixes. This worksheet provides a useful tool for students to expand their vocabulary and develop their language skills. The Prefixes and Suffixes reading comprehension pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/SQFVyJzJa_c</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/context-clues-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-using-context-clues-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P Lisa Flowers' Using Context Clues Reading Comprehension Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>These printable vocabulary worksheets are designed to help middle and high school students develop the ability to use context clues to decipher the meaning of unfamiliar words. Each worksheet presents new words within multiple sentences that provide increasingly specific contextual cues. During speech therapy sessions, I encourage students to cover the page and guess the meaning of each word based on one sentence at a time. Through this process, students gain confidence and improve their ability to identify unfamiliar words in a variety of academic contexts. The Using Context Clues reading comprehension pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/DjQ2ZXWHGCM</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/idioms-worksheets-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-idiom-worksheets-obfuscations-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers's Idioms worksheet - Obfuscations</video:title>
         <video:description>Word puzzles are a fun way to improve vocabulary skills, and this lesson provides just that! It contains a variety of obfuscated common idioms, such as 'at the decline of a cranial ornamentation' (meaning 'at the drop of a hat'). It also includes a list of idioms with their definitions, and challenges students to create their own obfuscations. This worksheet is a great way to encourage the use of a thesaurus and dictionary, and to learn the meaning of unfamiliar idioms, all while having fun solving and creating word puzzles. This idioms worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/hcbkKtzp7zU</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/reading-comprehension-skills-middle-school</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Paraphrases and Meanings reading comprehension worksheet</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Paraphrases and Meanings reading comprehension worksheet</video:title>
         <video:description>This set of printable worksheets and answer sheets is designed to improve the reading comprehension skills of middle and high school students. The focus is on identifying subtle differences in meaning between sentences by breaking down the content of each sentence. By doing so, language-impaired students and those with attention deficit disorders can enhance their ability to comprehend and summarize the main idea of a passage by using different wording while maintaining the original meaning. These worksheets promote the development of specific and precise language skills, which are crucial for academic success. The Paraphrases and Meanings reading comprehension pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/pYxYJz9DiZw</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/middle-school-reading-comprehension-activities-worksheet-pdfs</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-conceptual-relationships-middle-school-activities-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Conceptual Relationships Reading Comprehension Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This printable two-page worksheet is designed to help middle and high school students comprehend conceptual relationships between words and sentences. It covers a range of relationships including causality, contradiction, elaboration, and specificity. Students start by examining pairs of words with their corresponding conceptual relationship, and then proceed to identify the relationship between additional word pairs. The worksheet also includes fill-in-the-blank exercises that require students to identify and demonstrate conceptual relationships. An answer key is included. This worksheet is crucial for developing students' comprehension skills and helps them better understand written and verbal content. The Conceptual Relationships reading comprehension pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/EvtNZyOIQVM</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/reading-comprehension-activity-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-conceptual-relationships-high-school-activities-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Conceptual Relationships Advanced Reading Comprehension Worksheet</video:title>
         <video:description>This advanced reading comprehension worksheet is designed to enhance students' ability to understand complex written content by improving their capacity to identify sophisticated conceptual relationships between ideas. With a focus on identifying conceptual relationships between pairs of sentences, this worksheet presents advanced vocabulary, intricate and subtle meanings, and a broader range of conceptual relationships. It includes an answer key to help students check their work. The Conceptual Relationships Advanced reading comprehension pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/WhwehY79s3Q</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/downloadable-comprehension-activities</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-comprehension-activities-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P Lisa Flowers' Leisure Time Language Input Homework Assignment reading comprehension worksheet</video:title>
         <video:description>Leisure Time Language Input: Here's Lisa's rewrite: The homework assignment called “Leisure Time Language Input” encourages students to improve their vocabulary, reasoning skills, language comprehension, and general knowledge outside of the classroom. Unlike the common belief that reading novels or resource books is the only way to achieve this, the assignment suggests various enjoyable language content sources for students to read or view. The printable handout asks students to provide a brief summary of the content they consume. The assignment emphasizes that taking in language auditorally can be just as effective as reading, and is particularly helpful for students with decoding deficits.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/vfw1XyxQ6Nw</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/middle-school-writing-worksheet-pdfs</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-middle-school-writing-worksheet-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Writing Skills: Linguistic Specificity Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>One goal of writing is to be specific and descriptive, but language-impaired students often struggle with using non-specific words. For instance, the word 'upset' is commonly used to express a range of emotions. To improve their expressive skills, students need to replace these non-specific words with more precise ones like (in the case of “upset”) 'disappointed,' 'sullen,' 'outraged,' or 'frustrated.' This worksheet focuses on replacing non-specific terms, like 'good' and 'people,' with specific adjectives and nouns in sentences. It is ideal for group sessions where students can hear multiple variations of replacements and evaluate their effectiveness. The answer key includes multiple possible replacements. The Linguistic Specificity worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/XWk32c2UjBU</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/vocabulary-activities-for-middle-school-pdfs</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-vocabulary-activities-middle-school-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Writing Skills - Linguistic Flexibility Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Linguistic flexibility is a crucial skill for effective writing. This vocabulary worksheet is designed to enhance students' lexicon and encourage them to choose precise words to convey their thoughts. The task is simple - students are required to identify multiple synonyms for the underlined words within sentences. This exercise provides an opportunity for teachers and therapists to discuss the subtle differences in meanings between synonyms and encourages students to use a thesaurus while writing. An answer key with sample responses is included. The Linguistic Flexibility worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/N-JUcnyGTok</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/descriptive-writing-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-descriptive-writing-middle-school-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>SLP Lisa Flowers' Descriptive Writing: Adjectives and Adverbs Writing Skills Exercises Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Developing the skill of descriptive writing is crucial for effective written communication, but it can be challenging for many language impaired students. This four-page worksheet is designed to help students improve their descriptiveness. It starts with a clear explanation of descriptive writing and the use of adjectives, followed by an exercise where students need to insert adjectives from a provided list into various sentences. The worksheet also covers the use of adverbs, providing examples and various tasks to help students use different types of adverbs and understand the flexibility of their placement within sentences. The explanations, examples, and exercises in the worksheet are comprehensive and varied, providing students with enough practice to significantly enhance the descriptiveness of their writing by using adjectives and adverbs. The Descriptive Writing: Adjectives and Adverbs writing skills exercises worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/f-SCploYwm8</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/sentence-clarity-exercises-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-sentence-clarity-exercises-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Writing Skills: Clarity and Simplification Writing Skills Exercises</video:title>
         <video:description>This set of three printable worksheet pages is designed to help middle and high school students improve their writing clarity by simplifying phrases and sentences. By breaking down wordy sentences and analyzing meanings, students can learn to express their thoughts and ideas more clearly. These tasks not only improve writing skills, but also help improve comprehension. The Writing Skills: Clarity and Simplification writing skills exercises worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/nE8nociCQ3s</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/elaboration-in-writing-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-elaboration-in-writing-pdf-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Adding Meaning: Simplify and Elaborate Worksheets</video:title>
         <video:description>This set of writing skills worksheets is both educational and entertaining for students. It emphasizes that additional words do not always mean additional meaning in writing. The activity starts with an example sentence that is unnecessarily long and complicated, and then shows how it can be simplified to convey the same meaning more effectively. Students then work on simplifying other complex sentences and use a dice to add specific elements, such as adjectives, adverbs, and more specific nouns, to make the sentences more descriptive and meaningful. The worksheets also include an answer key with therapeutic notes. This activity is great for improving students' ability to elaborate on their writing and convey ideas more clearly. The Adding Meaning: Simplify and Elaborate worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/4G5oK9XiLmg</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/elaboration-worksheets-7th-8th-grade</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-elaboration-worksheets-seventh-grade-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Written Elaboration: Answering Homework Questions Writing Worksheet</video:title>
         <video:description>One possible reason why students may struggle to elaborate could be an absence of truly understanding how much information their reader needs or wants. This handout demonstrates to students how much semantic content most teachers require at the middle school or high school level. It begins with an extensive discussion on the importance of elaboration. Following are several answers to one Global History homework question, increasing in length and semantic content. Using a given rating scale, students rate each answer in terms of the number and complexity of relevant ideas contained. Students learn to distinguish between extra words and extra meaning, and begin to grasp the need to more fully answer homework and test questions. The Written Elaboration: Answering Homework Questions writing skills exercises worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ig6e39vYp18</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/8th-grade-english-writing-activity</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-perspective-consistency-worksheets-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' 8th Grade English Writing Worksheet: Perspective Consistency</video:title>
         <video:description>This two-page printable worksheet for 8th grade English students addresses the common issue of perspective inconsistency in writing, particularly in persuasive essays. Students often switch between the perspectives "you," "one," and "we" without realizing it. The worksheet encourages students to choose a perspective and stick to it by modifying a given essay. Afterward, students can practice further by reading the essay aloud and changing the pronouns to match a different perspective. The 8th Grade English Worksheet: Perspective Consistency writing skills exercises worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/RjPz6EGnJtY</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/download-active-and-passive-voice-exercises</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-active-and-passive-voice-exercises-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Passive and Active Voice Writing Skills Exercises Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Understanding the difference between passive and active voice is crucial for effective writing, yet many students are not aware of this grammar concept. This printable worksheet provides a clear explanation and discussion of passive and active voice, followed by two brief exercises to reinforce the concept. The first exercise requires identifying voice in sentences, while the second exercise focuses on transforming sentences from passive to active voice while preserving the original meaning. The worksheet includes an answer key for easy self-checking. The Passive and Active Voice writing skills exercises worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/dmac3VedI_Y</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/character-description-worksheet-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-character-description-worksheet-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Character Descriptions Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This writing activity is designed for students, teachers, tutors, and speech language pathologists to help students write a comprehensive and sophisticated character description essay. The activity teaches students how to infer information about a character's personality and perspective from their actions and dialogue. Students are given a short novel excerpt and are asked to attribute adjectives to one of the characters by analyzing their words and actions. Using the adjectives, students write a character description by following a written scaffold. This strategy and scaffold can be applied to almost any character analysis writing assignment. The lesson includes extensive notes on the provided excerpt and a sample character analysis essay following the scaffold to aid in teaching. The Character Descriptions writing skills exercises worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/35JNM-AJNKs</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/movie-review-worksheets</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-movie-review-worksheet-pdf-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Writing Skills: Movie Reviews Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>Writing a movie review can be an engaging task for students, as they can choose any movie they feel passionate about, whether positively or negatively. This worksheet provides a clear and straightforward outline for writing a comprehensive movie review. The outline includes an introduction paragraph, a plot summary and character analysis paragraph, a critique paragraph (which covers different elements of the movie such as humor, cinematography or realism), and a conclusion paragraph. To help students start their sentences and better express their thoughts, the worksheet also includes examples of phrasing. The Writing Skills: Movie Reviews writing skills exercises worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/7POVRS7ys3I</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/writing-a-letter-worksheet</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-writing-a-letter-worksheet-pdf-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Writing a Complaint Letter Worksheet PDF (Perspective Taking)</video:title>
         <video:description>This activity is a great way to teach students about the importance of considering their readers' perspectives and presuppositions when writing a complaint letter. It includes an actual complaint letter sent to a hotel chain, along with detailed notes on how to conduct the activity. Students can choose from two different situations and write their own letters, following the format of the original letter, which includes a description of the situation in the first paragraph and a request for compensation in the second paragraph. Through reviewing the original letter with the students, specific phrases, sentences, and semantic content are analyzed to show how they create certain impressions of the writer as honest and reasonable. This activity is a useful tool for helping students develop their writing skills and consider the needs and perspectives of their audience.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/FKwOk5kngG0</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>

  <url>
       <loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/middle-school-high-school-writing-worksheets-pdf</loc>
       <video:video>
         <video:thumbnail_loc>https://www.52worksheets.com/assets/img/videos/lisa-flowers-writing-worksheets-pdf-video.jpg</video:thumbnail_loc> 
         <video:title>S.L.P. Lisa Flowers' Transition Words and Phrases Writing Skills Exercises Worksheet PDF</video:title>
         <video:description>This writing skills worksheet is designed to help high school students understand and express the semantic relationships between ideas through the use of transition words and phrases. The handout at the beginning of the worksheet reinforces students' comprehension of the different types of relationships, including time, comparison, contrast, emphasis, conclusion, addition of information, clarification, and causality, by providing examples of transition words and phrases that express those relationships. The worksheet consists of three pages, with two tasks. The first task requires students to combine pairs of ideas using transition words and phrases from the handout, based on the relationship between those ideas. The second task involves identifying the relationship between more pairs of ideas and using transition words and phrases to combine them. By using Transition Words and Phrases, students can improve their ability to understand and express conceptual relationships in their writing. The Transition Words and Phrases writing skills exercises worksheet pdf is available as a part of the complete packet.</video:description>
         <video:player_loc allow_embed="yes" autoplay="ap=1">https://www.youtube.com/embed/CbHDjZoPfx8</video:player_loc>
       </video:video>
  </url>
</urlset>